itor.us 2016-06-04

# Privacy and Cookies Policy - Monitor.Us

##### **Introduction**

The Monitor.us ("we / us") respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it through our compliance with this policy.   
This policy (together with our terms of use and any other documents referred to in it) describes the personal information that we collect from you, or that you provide on this website [www.monitor.us]() (our "Website") and how that information may be used or disclosed by us.   
This policy does not apply to information collected on any third-party site or by any third-party application that may link to or be accessible from the Website.   
Please read the following carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your personal information and how we will treat it. By using or accessing our Website, you agree to this privacy policy. This policy may change from time to time and your continued use of the Website is deemed to be acceptance of such changes, so please check the policy periodically for updates. 

##### **Children under the age of 13**

Our Website is not intended for children under 13 years of age. No one under age 13 may provide any personal information to or on the Website. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If you are under 13, please do not register on the Website, make any purchases through the Website or send any information about yourself to us. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at help@monitor.us.

##### **Information we collect about you**

We collect several types of information from and about users of our Website, including: information you provide to us, that we collect as you navigate through the Website, -traffic and location data, IP addresses, usage details through the use of certain technologies, including cookies and web beacons, as well as information we receive from third parties, for example, our business partners - whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise and the resources that you access.

##### **Cookies**

Cookies are small files stored on the browser or the hard drive of your computer. Use of cookies help us to improve our Website and to deliver a better and more personalized service by enabling us to: estimate our audience size and usage patterns, store information about your preferences, allowing us to customize our Website according to your individual interests, speed up your searches and recognize you when you return to our Website.

A list of cookies we use, and their purpose, can be found below:

**Name** **Source** **Purpose**

__qca Various This cookie is used to measure the websites 'audience reach' using data including IP address, referring HTTP location, search string, time of access, and other statistics. 

WRUID [www.monitor.us]() This cookie is used by Clicktale, a website analytics system, to record an identication number for each visitor. 

_jsuid [www.monitor.us]() This cookie is used by Clicktale, a website analytics system, to record an identication number for each visitor. 

__utmc Various This takes a timestamp of the exact moment in time when a visitor leaves a site. 

SAPISID google.com This is used a part of the Google + sharing facility. 

bcookie [linkedin.com](https://www.linkedin.com/grp/home?gid=4368759) This is a cookie used by LinkedIn as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website. 

__utma Various This cookie keeps track of the number of times a visitor has been to the site pertaining to the cookie, when their first visit was, and when their last visit occurred. Google Analytics uses the information from this cookie to calculate things like Days and Visits. 

__utmz Various Keeps track of where the visitor came from, what search engine you used, what link you clicked on, what keyword you used, and where they were in the world when you accessed the website. 

__utmv Various This is a Google Analytics cookie. It is used for user-custom variables 

__utmb [linkedin.com](http://www.linkedin.com/groups/MonitorUs-4368759?home=&gid=4368759&trk=anet_ug_hm) This is a Google Analytics cookie. It takes a timestamp of the exact moment in time when a visitor enters a site. 

_leo_profile [linkedin.com](http://www.linkedin.com/groups/MonitorUs-4368759?home=&gid=4368759&trk=anet_ug_hm) This is a cookie used by LinkedIn as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website. 

_lipt [linkedin.com](http://www.linkedin.com/groups/MonitorUs-4368759?home=&gid=4368759&trk=anet_ug_hm) This is a cookie used by LinkedIn as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website. 

lang google.com This is a Google Analytics cookie 

rememberme google.com This is a Google Analytics cookie 

SS google.com This is a Google Analytics cookie 

HSID google.com This is a Google Analytics cookie 

SSID google.com This is a Google Analytics cookie 

APISID google.com This is a Google Analytics cookie 

PREF google.com This is a Google Analytics cookie 

NID google.com This is a Google Analytics cookie 

SID [linkedin.com](http://www.linkedin.com/groups/MonitorUs-4368759?home=&gid=4368759&trk=anet_ug_hm) This is a cookie used by LinkedIn as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website. 

visit [linkedin.com](http://www.linkedin.com/groups/MonitorUs-4368759?home=&gid=4368759&trk=anet_ug_hm) This is a cookie used by LinkedIn as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website. 

leo_auth_toekn [linkedin.com](http://www.linkedin.com/groups/MonitorUs-4368759?home=&gid=4368759&trk=anet_ug_hm) This is a cookie used by LinkedIn as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website. 

JSESSIONID [linkedin.com](http://www.linkedin.com/groups/MonitorUs-4368759?home=&gid=4368759&trk=anet_ug_hm) This is a cookie used by LinkedIn as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website. 

Persistence Cookie [linkedin.com](http://www.linkedin.com/groups/MonitorUs-4368759?home=&gid=4368759&trk=anet_ug_hm) This is a cookie used by LinkedIn as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website. 

X-LI-IDC [twitter.com](https://twitter.com/#!/monitorusblog) This is a cookie used by Twitter as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website. 

guest_id [twitter.com](https://twitter.com/#!/monitorusblog) This is a cookie used by Twitter as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website. 

pid [twitter.com](https://twitter.com/#!/monitorusblog) This is a cookie used by Twitter as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website. 

twll [twitter.com](https://twitter.com/#!/monitorusblog) This is a cookie used by Twitter as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website. 

k [twitter.com](https://twitter.com/#!/monitorusblog) This is a cookie used by Twitter as part of the sharing functionality on some pages on this website. 

expandcollapse [www.monitor.us]() Keep user preference to expand or collapse modules 

userId [www.monitor.us]() Unique user id to keep user login state 

activeTabId [www.monitor.us]() Last active tab id, to select that tab after login 

recentlyVisitedTabs [www.monitor.us]() tab names recently visited to use for tab search 

adv Various ADV number to track Marketing Campaigns 

loc Various LOC number to track Marketing Campaigns 

Referrer Various To track referrers 

If you register with us or if you continue to use our website, you agree to our use of cookies. You can refuse to accept cookies by activating the appropriate setting on your browser. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our Website. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you direct your browser to our Website.   
Web Beacons, also known as pixel tags are electronic images, contained on a website that permit us to count users who have visited those pages and for other related website statistics (for example, recording the popularity of certain website content and verifying system and server integrity). Web beacons are not used to access your personal information on the Website and are only used to compile aggregated statistics concerning use of the Website.  
We use a trusted third party to provide you with the ability to opt - out from collecting cookies, if you do not wish to have cookies, please click here: http://www.adobe.com/privacy/analytics.html.  
In addition, you may also set your browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If you do so, please note that some parts of this site may then be inaccessible or not function properly.  
This website uses social buttons to enable sharing of pages and third party services to display media. As such, cookies and scripts from third party sites have been used and these third parties may be gathering usage information. 

##### **Use of web analytics tools**

Monitor.us has enabled Google Analytics Advertiser Features that include:

  * Remarketing with Google Analytics
  * Google Display Network Impression Reporting
  * DoubleClick Platform integrations
  * Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting

Google Analytics Advertiser Features enable Google Analytics to collect data via [Google advertising cookies](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/key-terms/#toc-terms-cookie) and [anonymous identifiers](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/key-terms/#toc-terms-identifier), in addition to data collected through a standard Google Analytics implementation.  
If you do not want Google Analytics to collect and use your data you can use Google Analytics' [currently available opt-outs](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). 

##### **Information you provide to us**

We may collect and use the following information that you provide to us:   
Information that you provide by filling in forms on our Website. This includes information provided at the time of registering to use our Website, subscribing to our services, posting material or requesting further services or information. We may also ask you for information when you enter a contest or promotion sponsored by us, and when you report a problem with our Website.  
Records and copies of your correspondence (including e-mail addresses), if you contact us.  
Your responses to surveys that we might ask you to complete for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them.  
Details of transactions you carry out through our Website and of the fulfilment of your orders. You may be required to provide financial information before placing an order through our Website.

##### **Uses made of the information**

We use information that we collect about you or that you provide to us, including any personal information, in the following ways:

  * To present our Website and its contents in a suitable and effective manner for you and for your computer.
  * To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us.
  * To carry out our obligations, process and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.
  * To notify you about changes to our service.
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our services, when you choose to do so.
  * For marketing and promotional purposes so as to provide you with information about services we think you might like.

##### **Technology usage**

IP Addresses

Like the vast majority of website providers, we collect details of your visits to our Website. We only collect aggregate information, such as, for example, traffic data, logs and other communication data, whether this is required for our own contractual purposes or otherwise. The information we collect concerns the resources that you access, information about your computer and internet connection, including your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration, marketing purposes and to report aggregate information to our advertisers.  
Where, according to local law, IP addresses and the like are considered personal information, then we treat it as such.  
The information we collect is merely statistical data about our users' equipment, browsing actions and patterns and does not and cannot identify any individual. 

##### **User Contributions**

You are responsible for any content, including personal information, that you contribute to be posted, published or displayed on the Website, or transmit to other users of the Website (collectively, "User Contributions"). Your User Contributions are posted on and transmitted to other users of the Website at your own risk. Although we limit access to certain pages, you may set certain privacy settings for such information by logging into your account profile, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. Additionally, we cannot control the actions of other users of the Website with whom you may choose to share your User Contributions; therefore, we cannot guarantee who will view your User Contributions. We are not responsible for circumvention by third parties of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Website. You understand and acknowledge that, even after removal, copies of your User Contributions may remain viewable in cached and archived pages, or may have been copied or stored by other Website users. Proper access and use of information provided on the Website, including User Contributions, is governed by this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use and known or suspected violations should be reported to help@monitor.us.

##### **Disclosure of your information**

We may disclose personal information that you provide via this Website to the following third parties:  
To a member of our group - holding company and its subsidiaries and affiliates.  
Direct contractors and service providers we use to support our business.  
In the event (whether perspective or actual) of a merger, acquisition, or any form of sale of some or all of Monitis' assets, in which case personal information held by Monitis' about its customers will be among the assets transferred to the (prospective) buyer.  
We may also disclose your personal information to third parties to:   

  * Comply with any court order or other legal obligation.
  * Enforce or apply our terms of use or terms of sale and other agreements.
  * Protect the rights, property, or safety of Monitis, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

##### **Your choices about how we use and disclose your information**

We strive to provide you with choices regarding the personal information you provide to us. We have created mechanisms to provide you with the following control over your information:

##### **Accessing and correcting your personal information**

You can review and update your personal information by logging into the Website and visiting your account profile page and making changes. If you have forgotten your password, once you have tried to register and failed, you can click on the "Forgot your password?" link to reach a page on which you can submit your e-mail address. Your user name and password then will be e-mailed to you.

##### **Unsubscribing**

In each and every email that we send to you, there is an 'unsubscribe' hyperlink, which you may you use if you wish to 'opt out' of and stop receiving email communications from us. The hyperlink will direct you to our website, where upon entering the email address that you no longer wish to receive Monitis emails, one last confirmation email shall then be sent to the email address you designate. Merely confirm that you do indeed wish to stop Monitis email's being sent to you and that email address shall automatically be unsubscribed.  
Alternatively, you may email Monitis at help@monitor.us with your request, stating 'Unsubscribe' in the header and what email addresses you wish not to receive Monitis emails and within a reasonable period, we shall ensure that such email addresses are unsubscribed and shall no longer receive any communications from us. 

##### **Where we store your personal data**

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside of the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff maybe engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.  
All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted using SSL technology. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.  
Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access. 

##### **Data security**

We have implemented measures designed to secure your personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration and disclosure. All information you provide to us is stored on secure servers behind firewalls. Any payment transactions and is encrypted using SSL technology.  
The safety and security of your information also depends on you. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password for access to certain parts of our Website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone. We urge you to be careful about giving out information in public areas of the Website like message boards. The information you share in public areas may be viewed by any user of the Website. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information transmitted to our Website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access. 

##### **Your rights**

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at help@monitor.us. Our Website may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites. 

##### **Your California privacy rights**

California Civil Code Section § 1798.83 permits users of our Website that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to help@monitor.us.

##### **Access to information**

The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any access request may be subject to a fee as applicable and in accordance with the laws of the country from which you are accessing the Website, to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

##### **Changes to our privacy policy**

It is our policy to post any changes we make to our privacy policy on this page. It is your responsibility to check this page from time to time to check for any change. Your continued use of the Website or our services shall be deemed to be your consent to such changes.The date the privacy policy was last revised is identified at the top of the page. 

##### **Contact information**

To ask questions or comment about this privacy policy and our privacy practices, contact us at:  
help@monitis.com 

Last modified: October 2012
